<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown on Joan Perals — Web Developer, Creative Technologist, Digital Craftsman</title>
    <link>/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markdown on Joan Perals — Web Developer, Creative Technologist, Digital Craftsman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 22:12:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing blog posts from Django to Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/68/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 22:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/68/</guid>
      <description>Last year I started a sort of basic markdown-based micro-blog just to jot down small software-related learnings. I hosted it on Heroku, which is free but sleeps after 30 minutes of inactivity. That&amp;rsquo;s OK for me as a user, but I would not want potential visitors to have to wait for the instance to wake up. At the same time, not sure it&amp;rsquo;s worth paying for Django hosting just for such a minor project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indentation-based vs fenced code blocks in Markdown</title>
      <link>/posts/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 12:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/14/</guid>
      <description>So apparently there are (at least) two ways to add a code block in Markdown: either by indentation (which I find less convenient), or by using the triple-backtick (```) method that I am already used to (Gitlab, Github, Slack, Trello&amp;hellip;),. It seems that using triple tilde (~~~) may also be possible, at least in some implementations.
Markdown code blocks created with the triple backtick or triple tilde method are called &amp;ldquo;fenced code blocks&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>